KUNJKUMAR PATEL

kunjp19@gmail.com | (234)7181833 | Canton, MI | linkedin.com/in/kunjp19 | github.com/kunjp19 | kunjp19.github.io

SUMMARY

A driven and focused software engineer experienced in Python, Java, and Javascript having an in-depth knowledge of software development lifecycle, microservices, design patterns, cs fundamentals such as data structures and algorithms, OOP. I have a keen interest in software development specifically in backend development, cloud-native platforms & mobile application development.

EXPERIENCE

Software Developer II, Nexient

Sep 2021 - Present

- Major duties include java-based backed development having sync up and communicate different application systems by following enterprise integration patterns.
- Working on enterprise microservices and integration frameworks like apache camel, testing framework citrus, Unit-testing, service-test with cucumber, performance test using Apache JMeter.

Full-Stack Developer, Sikka Software Corporation

July 2021 - Sep 2021

- Worked on the product development of the dental practice optimizer portal including analyzing in terms of different KPIs, successfully migrated the company's old portal to a new design.
- Developed User interfaces in React.is and backend API logic development.

Graduate Research Assistant, iLab @ Computer Science, CSUEB

May 2020 - May 2021

- Invented an Al-based solution that is used to measure potential risks of Covid-19 such as Crowd density, Mask detection, social distancing, Fever detection related to geographical location
- Identified areas to improve and scale backend architecture and application design, developed tools and utilities to diagnose and fix problems, ensured proper technical design and documentation.
- Collaborated in a team of crowd density estimation system and android platform, built hosting platform to deploy Machine Learning and Deep learning model that increased performance by 7%
- Skills and Technology: Firebase, Java, Object Detection API, Python, Flask, GCP

Software Engineer, Glint Logic

July 2017 - August 2019

- Developed full-stack web application by following TDD, created RESTful Web services, and integrate with business logic and the persistence layer using the rest controller, Spring Data JPA.
- Worked with third-party API services, JAVA 8 features such as Collection API, write unit test cases and integration test cases using Mockito, Junit, built docker containers, and solid CI/CD pipelines using Jenkins.
- Delivered project from design to deployment utilizing agile methodology, using technology stack as React.js, Java, SpringBoot, Microservices, Docker, Kafka, AWS
- Involved in design of database schema, cache layer to reduced data retrieval process time by 9%

SKILLS

Programming languages: Python, Javascript, Java, HTML, CSS

- Web Development: SprigBoot, React.js, Express.js, Node.js, Flaskss
- Frameworks: Apache Camel, Citrus, JMeter, Cucumber, OpenShift
- Databases and Cloud Platforms: MongoDB, MySQL, Heroku, AWS Lambda, EC2, S3
- DevOps and Tools: Jupyter Notebook, GitHub, Android Studio, IntelliJ, Postman, JIRA, Maven, Docker, Jenkins

EDUCATION

Master of Science, Computer Science California State University, East Bay Bachelor of Engineering, Computer engineering **Gujarat Technological University**

August 2019 - May 2021 GPA 3.65

August 2015 - June 2019

GPA 3.60

CERTIFICATION

Microservices Foundations, Issuing authority:LinkedIn

May 2021

Python Object-Oriented Programming, Issuing authority: LinkedIn

Jan 2021

Full Stack development with MERN, Issuing authority: Udemy

Oct 2019